A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Vice President, Rodney W. Nichols FA144
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Vice President, Rodney W. Nichols
1962-1980, 1970-1975
1970-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nichols, Rodney W.
Rockefeller University
FA144
16.36 Cubic Feet 35 boxes
35 boxes.
Biographical/Historical note
Rodney W. Nichols (1937- ) came to Rockefeller University in 1970 as special assistant to the president. He was later elected vice president in 1972 under the presidency of Frederick Seitz, and became executive vice president under Joshua Lederberg in 1978. His duties revolved around the planning and administration of University events and activities. Nichols, a research and development specialist, also acted as a consultant of Research and Development for numerous organizations including the Office of the Secretary of Defense.
Arrangement note
The Rodney W. Nichols papers consist of eight series:
1. Foundations, 1969-1975
2. Individuals Files, 1965-1979
3. AAAS, 1969-1973
4. Corporations, 1970-1975
5. Development Files, 1971-1974
6. Correspondence, 1970-1972
7. General Files, 1967-1980
8. Iran Files, 1962-1977
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 347
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: correspondence, subject files, and applications.
Iran; American Association for the Advancement of Science; W.K. Kellogg Foundation; Ford Foundation; Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching
- Foundations, 1969-1975; 1; 4.08 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes primarily correspondence; also includes brochures, notes, wills, publications, proposals, memoranda, reports, grant information, receipts, meeting schedules, and travel information.
  Foundations include the Carnegie Corporation of New York, The Ford Foundation, The W. K Kellogg Foundation, and others.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - ARCS, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Astor Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Closed materials within.
  - Benedum Foundation, Claude Worthington, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Booth Ferris Foundation - Proposal, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Bernie Brown Foundation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Burroughs Wellcome Fund, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Calder Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1970-1974; folder 1 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1974; folder 2 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York - Research on Cultural Factors in the Development of Learning Abilities, 1971-1974; folder 3 of 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cary Trust Proposal, 1969-1970; folder 1 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cary Trust, 1970 1973; folder 2 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cary Trust (Correspondence), 1970; folder 3 of 5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cary Trust (Correspondence), 1971-1973; folder 4 of 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cary Trust, 1974; folder 5 of 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapel Gifts Change, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Foundation for Child Development, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Jane Coffin Childs Memorial Fund for Medical Research, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1970-1974; folder 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Edna McConnell Clark Foundation [An Exploratory Proposal], 1972; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cleveland Foundation, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Commonwealth Fund (Exception: Rockefeller University Accounting System Report- ), 1971-1974 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Dana Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Danforth Foundation, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Arthur Vining Davis Foundations, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dreyfus Medical Foundation, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Doris Duke Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Fairchild Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fleishmann Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1973-1974; folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1971-1974; folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Ford Foundation - Field Research Center (Millbrook, NY), 1972-1974; folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Electric Foundation, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Service Foundation, 1971 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Goldhirsch Foundation, 1972-1974; folder 1 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Goldhirsch Foundation [Four Proposals for Cancer-Related Research], 1973; folder 2 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The Goldhirsch Foundation [Four Proposals to the Goldhirsch Foundation], 1973; folder 3 of 3 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Herman and Ruth Goodman Foundation, Inc., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Grant Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Gulbenkian Foundation, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Harris Foundation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The John A. Hartford Foundation, Inc., 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Charles Hayden Foundation (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Irma T. Hirschl Trust, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Innisfree Foundation, 1971; folder 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Innisfree Foundation (exception: one letter from), 1972-1974 1980; folder 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Keller Property, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The W. K Kellogg Foundation, 1971-1972; folder 1 of 4 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The W. K Kellogg Foundation [A Proposal to W. K Kellogg Foundation], 1972; folder 2 of 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The W. K Kellogg Foundation, 1972; folder 3 of 4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The W. K Kellogg Foundation [only parts J&K illus. res. projects and curricula vitae] and other originals changed and/or destroyed for later Clark prop], folder 3 of 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Kleberg Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Charles F. Kettering Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Bertha Koempel Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Kresge Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Kroc Foundation (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Lasker Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Lilly Endowment, 1971-1974; folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Lilly Endowment [Proposal], 1974; folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Lincoln Fund, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Henry Luce Foundation, Inc., 1971-1974; folder 1 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Henry Luce Foundation, Inc. [An Exploratory Proposal], 1972; folder 2 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Henry Luce Foundation, Inc., 1972; folder 3 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, 1971-1974; folder 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation [An Exploratory Proposal], 1973; folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Brooks & Hope B. McCormick Foundation, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Philip McMaster Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation [also includes accounting system report from], 1972-1974 1977; folder 1 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1970-1974; folder 2 of 3 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Andrew W. Mellon Foundation [Proposal], 1971; folder 3 of 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Richard King Mellon Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Merck & Co., Inc., 1973-1974; folder 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Merck & Co., Inc. [Proposal], 1973; folder 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Charles E. Merrill Trust, 1971-1974; folder 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Merrill Trust, 1971-1972; folder 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ambrose Monell Foundation (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Seeley G. Mudd Fund, 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nestle Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The New York Community Trust, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - New York Foundation/Heyman, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - The New York Times Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Edward John Noble Fund, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Nutrition Foundation, Inc., 1971 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Perkin Fund, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Olin Foundation, 1972 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Pew Memorial Trust (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Polinger Gifts - Cancer Books, 1970-1972 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Gar Reichman Foundation, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Fannie E. Rippel Foundation, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1974; folder 1 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation Progress Report (also printing order from 4/74), 1972-1973; folder 2 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1971-1973; folder 3 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation [Progress Reports - Bound Copies], 1971-1973; folder 4 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-1973; folder 5 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-1974; folder 6 of 11 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-1974; folder 7 of 11 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1972 1974; folder 8 of 11 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1969-1970; folder 9 of 11 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation [Reproductive Biology - Faculty Bios], 1970; folder 10 of 11 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation [Environmental Sciences], 1970; folder 11 of 11 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - The Scaife Family Charitable Trust, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Schiff Foundation, 1972 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The Shubert Foundation, Inc., 1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1971 1973-1974; folder 1 of 4 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Alfred P. Sloan Foundation [Proposal], 1970; folder 2 of 4 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - The Alfred P. Sloan Foundation [Pfaffmann Proposal], 1971-1972; folder 3 of 4 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - The Alfred P. Sloan Foundation [Pfaffmann Proposal], 1970-1971; folder 4 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The Spencer Foundation, 1975-1977; folder 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Spencer Foundation, 1971-1973; folder 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Sulzberger Foundation, Inc., 1970-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - The Surdna Foundation, Inc., 1971-1974 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Jacqueline Susann Cancer Research Fund, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Teagle Foundation, 1969-1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Tudor Foundation Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - UPS Foundation [Also referred to in file as the Foundation], 1974 1907 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Van Amerigen Foundation, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Emily and Ernest Woodruff Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Individual Files, 1965-1979; 2; 4 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes primarily correspondence; also includes memoranda, wills, notes, newspaper clippings, curriculum vita, proposals, invitations, background materials, publications meeting schedules, brochures, travel information, and booklets.
  Individuals include Walter Annenberg, Charles Bassine, J. Seward Johnson, and others.
  - Andre Aisenstadt, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Frank Altschul, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Walter Annenberg, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Lily Auchincloss, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Paul Austin, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Robert Bach, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Mrs. Wentworth C. Bacon, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Charles C. Bassine, 1969 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Henry P. Becton, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - James J. Beha, Esq, 1973-1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - William S. Beinecke, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Robert A. Berhard, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Boel/Solvay File, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Edgar M. Bronfman, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - William A. M Burden, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Prof. H. B. G Casimir, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hays Clark, 1971 1974 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - William Van Alan Clark, Jr., 1974 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Alfred Einstein Cohn, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Corbetta Property, 1974-1977 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Richard Courts, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Shelby Cullom Davis, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Donald K. David, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Thomas E. Dewey, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Stephen DuBrul, Jr., 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - James T. Flexner, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Thomas Ford, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Benjamin S. Frank, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Donald C. Fresne, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Henry Clay Frick II, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - A. Corwin Frost, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Tetsuo Fukaishi, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Maxwell M. Geffen, 1974 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Roger Geffen, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Elbridge T. Gerry, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Eli Gerver, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Elsie Gilbert, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Roswell Gilpatrick, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Mrs. Louis S. Gimbel, Jr., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Cecil Green, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Harriman, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Harold Helm, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Houghton, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Lady Barbara Ward Johnson, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Howard Hughes Philanthropies, 1972-1973 1976 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Denison B. Hull, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - F. E Imel, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - John N. Irwin II, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Nancy S. Meson, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - J. Seward Johnson, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Irving Kahn, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Dr. Frederick Kavanagh, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Mrs. Philip Kind, Jr., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Kent Leavitt, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Donald J. Lewis, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Bayless Manning, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - William McChesney Martin, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Abby Rockefeller Mauze Professorship, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Harold W. McGraw, Jr., 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Andre Meyer, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - C. Phillip Miller, Jr., 1972 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Kiichi Miyazawa, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Mrs. Henry Moses, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Peter Mumane, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - JohnOlin, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Tsuyoshi Ohnishi, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Katharine Ordway, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Roger Oresman, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Bruno Pagliai, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - William S. Paley, 1972-1974 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Merrill Paritt, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Joan Payson, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - C. Michael Paul, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - H. Ross Perot, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Mrs. Juiliette Philipbar, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Ogden R. Reid, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. Harold L. Redfield, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Phyllis Rifield, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - M. Riklis, 1970 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - E. Claiborne Robins, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Mrs. Arthur Ross, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Oscar Ruebhausen, Esq, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Neil Ruzic, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Nancy Salkin, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Webster Sandford, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Richard B. Salomon except, 1973-1977 1975 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - A. W Scheffres, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Arnold Schwartz, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Jennifer Jones Simon, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - James G. Stahlman, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Steven E. Stern, 1971-1974 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Chauncey Stillman, 1971-1974 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Frank B. Stubbs, 1971-1979 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Alice Tully, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Stella Tyrrel, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Kogoro Uemura, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. Cyrus Vance, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Sir Siegmund Warburg, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Whitehead Institute, 1971-1972; folder 1 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Whitehead Institute, 1973-1977; folder 2 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Whitehead Institute, 1971-1974; folder 3 of 3 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - DeWitt Wallace, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Thomas J. Watson, Jr., 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Weekes-Johnson File, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Harold T. White, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Arthur Winard, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Walter B. Wriston, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Richard Zigmond, 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - The Rockefeller University Children's School, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The American Journal of Occupational Therapy, 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Animal Facilities, 1965 1968 1970-1972; folder 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Animal Facilities [Proposal], 1972; folder 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - AAAS [American Association for the Advancement of Science], 1972-1974 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - AAAS: Committee on Scientific Freedom and Responsibility, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - AIP [American Institute of Physics], 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - American Scientist, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Henry Arnold, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Dr. William Bevan, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Biomedical Research Panel, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Bohemian Grove (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Boss & Phelps, 1972-1973 1976; folder 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Boss & Phelps, 1972-1973; folder 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Raymond Bowers, 1970 1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Dr. D. Allan Bromley, 1970-1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Brookings Institution, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Center for a Peacetime Economy, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Cosmos Club, 1972-1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Diebold Institute for Public Policy Studies, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Enviro Control, Inc. (DMM), 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Franklin Institute, 1968 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - John S. Foster, Jr., 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Richard Fryklund, 1970-1974 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Eugene G. Fubini, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - David Grath, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Dr. Morton H. Halperin, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Congressman Richard T. Hanna, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Harvard-MIT-Health Science, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dr. John G. Hildebrand (Trustee), 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Innovation Magazine, 1971; folder 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Innovation Magazine, 1971-1972; folder 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Institute for the Future, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Society, Ethics & the Life Sciences, 1971 1972 1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - National Health Forum, 1973; folder 1 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - National Health Forum [The Changing Role of the Public Sectors in Health Care], 1973; folder 2 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - National Health Forum, 1973 1972-1973; folder 3 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - [New York Times articles], 1971 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - NIH-Cooper Report, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Robert A. Kilmarx, 1970-1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Richard M. Krause, 1970 1972-1974 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - S. Benedict Levin, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Donald M. MacArthur, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - MacLean - Institute of Biomagnetics, 1969 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Maine - The Research Institute of the Gulf of Maine, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - The Manpower Institute, 1970-1971 1973; folder 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - The Manpower Institute, 1971; folder 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Michael Michaelis, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Muscular Dystrophy Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - NAS [National Academy of Sciences] Board on International Organizations & Programs, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - National Science Foundation, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - NAS: National Security Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - National Strategy Information Center, Inc., 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - New York Chamber Soloists, Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - New York City Bicentennial Corporation, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - New York State Research Institute for Neurochemistry & Drug Addiction, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - New York University, 1970-1972 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - New York Institute of Ocean Resources, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Office of Defense Research & Engineering, 1969-1970 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - OMB [Office of Management and Budget], 1973 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Oil Research Fund, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Harold Orlans, 1970-1973 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - John N. Ott, 1965 1971 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Pauling-Orthomolecular Institute, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Physics Survey Committee [National Academy of Sciences], 1970-1972 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Dr. Emanuel R. Piore, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Presidential Prizes, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Don K. Price, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Research Corporation, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Philip C. Ritterbush, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Stephen Rosen, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Albert Rosenfeld, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Sidney G. Roth, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Benno Schmidt, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Richard Scribner, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Frederick Seitz [Resignation], 1976-1978; folder 1 of 5 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Frederick Seitz, 1970-1974 1976; folder 2 of 5 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Frederick Seitz: Replies to June 8th reception - Tower 178, folder 3 of 5 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Frederick Seitz: Board of Trustees Dinner, 1978; folder 4 of 5 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Frederick Seitz: Correspondence with RWN, folder 5 of 5 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Dr. James Shannon, 1970-1974 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Shannon Seminar on R & D Policy, 1970-1974 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Dr. John Sherman, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Sigma Xi Lectureship, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Sixth International Arms Control Symposium, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Professor Bruce Smith, 1971-1974 1976 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Fred Smith, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Herbert Striner, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Dr. C. E. Sunderlin, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Tax Reform, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Frank N. Trager, 1971-1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Jack D. Tiner, 1972-1973 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Universities Research Association, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Norman Waks, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - John C. Warner, 1971-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Webb's Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Jerome B. Weisner, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Emory Williams, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Deanne Howard Winoker, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Dael Wolfle, 1971 1973 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Richard J. Wortman, MD, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- AAAS, 1969-1973; 3; 0.2 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes publications, reports, symposium material, meeting programs, notes, background information, registration forms, and correspondence.
  - AAAS [American Association for the Advancement of Science], 1969-1973; folder 1 of 5 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - AAAS December Mtgs. [Institutional Impacts of Federal R & D Support to Universities], 1972 1970-1972; folder 2 of 5 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - AAAS, 1972; folder 3 of 5 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - AAAS Chicago, 1970 December 1970-1971; folder 4 of 5 (Box 21, Folder 16)